Zachary Barry

Associate Data Scientist · M.S. Applied Mathematics

(541) 678-2898 | zackbarry13@gmail.com | github.com/ZackBarry | linkedin.com/in/zackbarry

Summary _

Data enthusiast with a passion for big data, machine learning, and well-documented code. 3+ years experience applying computational methods to numerical problems, focusing on scalability and reproducability. Interested in developing production-ready models for a company that supports a culture of learning.

Technologies _

Languages

Languages R (tidyverse, sparklyr, mlr3, shiny), SQL, Python (for ETL), Scala (Apache Spark)

Machine Learning Regression, KNN, K-means, SVM, Bagging, Boosting, Random Forest, XGBoost, lightGBM

Skills Data Cleaning/Wrangling/Visualization, Airflow, Docker, Google Cloud

Experience

G5Associate Data Scientist

Bend, OR

• Attribution Platform (R, Spark, Airflow):

Oct. 2019 - Present

- Used Markov Chain Attribution to enable cross-channel advertising spend optimization, leading to 37% more conversions at 45% lower cost per conversion
- Leveraged Spark to handle 100 million distinct user paths (1+ billion observations) in a scalable manner
- Implemented an Airflow DAG to deploy the model in a Google Cloud production context
- Customer Data Platform (Scala, Spark):
 - Reduced run time of production user model by 95% (6hr to 35min) without increasing compute resources
 - Maintained 99.98% accuracy on a 5TB data set, tested for 1 year of growth
 - Delivered as an executable JAR for deployment in a GCP Dataproc context

G5 Bend, OR

Data Analyst

Jan. 2019 - Sep. 2019

- **Business Intelligence** (R, Shiny):
 - Reduced report creation time by over 80% while establishing a single source of truth for performance data
 - Created and maintained the back- and front-end of an in-memory performance benchmarking application
 - Applied Mann-Whitney U test and Global Moran's I test to identify statistically relevant comparisons
 - Encouraged adoption by providing use cases and technical documentation for internal training course
- Operator Response Time (R, Tidyverse):
 - Analyzed wave patterns to determine caller wait time for call scoring project (85% accurate within 3 sec)
 - Presented results as a POC Shiny application to internal stakeholders in Product Management

Northwest Mathematics, LLC

Bend, OR

Independent Contractor (C#)

Aug. 2018 - Nov. 2018

- Expanded a probabilistic model to support the concurrent simulation of slot machines across casinos
- Updated Windows forms in Visual Studio to allow users to specify the circumstances of each casino
- Used C# package EPPlus to programmatically create excel spreadsheets for end users

Education _____

Oregon State University

Corvallis, OR.

B.S. and M.S. in Applied and Computational Mathematics — 3.96 GPA

Sept. 2014 - June 2018

- Researched numerical techniques to reduce solution error for systems of nonlinear PDEs (NSF grant)
- First student to complete Accelerated Masters in Mathematics (5 year program) in 4 years
- Courses in numerical linear algebra, finite element methods, computational tomography, and probability